CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone: +8801965287811

Email: towsif.chowdhury@northsouth.edu
Website: https://towsif13.netlify.app/

Additional Resources: Github, LinkedIn, ResearchGate

RESEARCH INTEREST

My primary field of research interest is Artificial Intelligence (AI). Within AI, I am interested in problems related to **Computer Vision**, **Artificial Neural Networks**, and **Reinforcement learning**. In particular, my research incorporates problems related to machine learning and deep learning.

EDUCATION

January 2017 - April 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

North South University(NSU)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- CGPA 3.60/4.00
- Specialized Trail Artificial Intelligence

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2021 - Present

Lab Officer

Department of Mathematics and Physics, North South University Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Independently teach 3 undergraduate lab classes
- Provide consultation to students
- Assist in the preparation of lab manuals
- Responsible for grading and marking the students in their lab classes

May 2021 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant (GRA)

Department of ECE, North South University Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Designing algorithms based on experience replay memory and catastrophic forgetting for autonomous agents
- Development of code and experimental platforms, running experiments and analyzing data using machine learning

October 2021 - January 2022

Graduate Teaching Assistant (GA)

Department of ECE, North South University Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Facilitate a discussion section or tutorial; hold weekly office hours; grade homework, programming assignments, exams, or projects; prepare answer keys or supplementary notes
- Assisting faculty with record keeping, such as tracking attendance and calculating grades

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant (UGA)

Department of ECE, North South University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Facilitate a discussion section or tutorial; hold weekly office hours; grade homework, programming assignments, exams, or projects; keep records; distribute and copy reading materials; prepare answer keys or supplementary notes
- Assisting faculty with record keeping, such as tracking attendance and calculating grades

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Journal Paper

- Youme, S. K., Chowdhury, T. A., Ahamed, H., Abid, M. S., Chowdhury, L., & Mohammed, N. (2021). Generalization of Bangla Sign Language Recognition Using Angular Loss Functions. IEEE Access, 9, 165351–165365. doi:10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3134903
- Youme, S. K., Chowdhury, T. A., Ahamed, H., Abid, M. S., Sohrawardi, R. B., & Siddique, S. (2021). RER: Recycled Experience Replay, Blending Oldest Memories with Recent Selective Experiences to Improve Remembering. (Work-in-Progress)

Conference Paper

• Youme, S. K., H., Abid, M. S., Chowdhury, T. A., Ahamed, & Siddique, S. (2021). Local Climate Zone Mapping using Clustering Algorithms: A case study of Dhaka, Bangladesh. (Under Review)

GRANTS

Name of Grant CTRG 2021-2022

Grant offered by North South University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Project Title High performance less resource-intensive Deep Reinforcement Learning methods for

applications in autonomous agents and search and rescue robotics

Grant amount BDT 500,000

Role Research Assistant

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages Python, Java, C

Familiar with C++, CSS, HTML, SQL, Assembly, LateX, MATLAB, Flutter

Operating Systems Windows, Linux

Libraries PyTorch, Tensorflow, Pandas, Scikit-learn

Database Tools Firebase, MySQL

Others Machine learning, Deep learning, Data Science, Android Development

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

IELTS 8.0 (L-9, R-7, W-6.5, S-8.5)

REFERENCES

Academic and Professional references are available upon request.